Today I have the pleasure of showing you
one of my personal favorite automations.
And I mean that. We try to build a lot
of different automations to support the
content and community business that we
run, but not all of them stick. But one
of the big ones that we not just keep
around, but keep iterating on over time
is this meeting summary automation right
here. And today I will be guiding you
through this automation, giving you the
blueprint and telling you what
possibilities you kind of have here. But
first, let me explain what this is. It
basically takes in brand new meeting
notes from our team meetings and then
runs a GPT API call on top of it and
then basically takes the content of the
meeting and extracts valuable insights
for me as the CEO and founder of our
little organization here. Ultimately,
this is what that looks like. It doesn't
just give me the action items, which is
pretty standard, but it also extracts
custom ideas that are aligned with my
own goals. And it also surfaces
uncomfortable truths from within the
transcripts. These are custom prompting
techniques that are not present in any
of the meeting summarization tools I'm
aware of, and I really wanted this. As
you know, by now, I have a large
collection of various specialty prompts.
But it's unrealistic to just pull every
meeting transcript and do this manually.
That's why we created this automation
that does all of this. And it even has
an element in there where it shows how
well that meeting aligned with our
current road map. But as you can see,
this is quite custom and I will do my
best to explain it to you in this video
and you will get the blueprint. But I
just have to say that this is a rather
advanced video and I realize that most
people won't be able to recreate this
either because this might be too
intricate or because we use certain
specialty tools here. We use Google
Meets with the Gemini Assistant in there
for the meeting transcripts. Then those
files get stored in the Google drive
automatically. We use air table as our
database to store all of these meeting
notes and make to glue all of this
together for this entire process to
happen automatically. And also I want to
say a big thank you to make for
sponsoring this video. I really like
working with them because they just
reached out and asked, "Hey, do you have
any more detailed or advanced
automations that you would like to show
off?" And I said, "Yes, I actually have
this one." And they were all for that.
Usually a lot of companies they want to
do a extremely beginner friendly
tutorial and Make does exactly the
opposite which I really love. They say
hey show something specific and show us
something useful rather than showing a
generic beginner tutorial. We've seen
those and we want to go deeper and
that's what we're going to do in this
video. A final note before we get into
the overview of this is that hey yeah if
you're using a different tool stack and
for example you might be using notion
for the database and for example you're
using a different meeting assistant to
create your transcripts or you're using
Dropbox instead of Google Drive. Well,
you'll have to switch out those nodes
and this tutorial just shows you what we
have done and gives you that blueprint.
If you want to customize it because you
have a different tool stack. Well, this
is a fantastic starting point. You can
use the blueprints that we give you.
Actually, just upload that to Chat GPT
and then start talking to it, what steps
you would need to take to customize
this, but this tutorial is just for our
workflow. So, with that being said,
let's get into this. And I'll just start
by giving you an overview. And then
we'll get into the blueprint and how to
set this up for yourself. So, the
trigger here is quite simple. It's a
timed Google Drive connection that
checks the meet recordings folder in my
Google Drive. This is just where the
Gemini meetings automatically go into.
So, this is the tutorial automation, but
the proper one is enabled to run every
15 minutes. We just have a few meetings
a week. Nevertheless, this just costs
one credit at a time, and we don't mind.
Next up, there's a text parser and
tools. And you'll see a bunch of these
throughout the automation because not
all of the formatting that comes from
Google Gemini is ready to be worked with
in some of the other tools. For example,
we want to bring it from the meeting
summary and the transcript within here
into Air Table which stores dates
beautifully like this. In order to do
that, you need to parse out certain
parts including the date format right
here. For example, right here you can
see what we do with the date format to
make this fit into Air Table. Then we
move on to actually downloading the
files. And not just that, we also
convert it to markdown. So we can easily
make this work within this automation.
Then we just make sure this markdown
file is in UTF8 format. So all of this
is well readable in the GPT API call
that is coming up in a second here. Now
we enter this router and this is
basically here to filter out just the
files that have everything we need. So
if it's just the transcript, it goes
here. But if there's everything we need,
we go down this main branch down here,
which is essentially the entire
workflow. I mean, up until now, we kind
of just prepared and downloaded our
file. And now we're here in this main
branch. And I'm going to show you this
on the example of a successful run on
Monday. I tried to manually replicate it
here for you with like duplicating a
file and making it happen. But that made
me realize that the way this automation
is set up works perfectly when Gemini
saves the file and puts everything in
place. But for me to replicate it here,
I would need to rename certain things
and change parts of this automation. And
I think that would cause more confusion
than that's worth. So I'm going to show
you this on the example of the
automation that actually ran on Monday
on our latest team meeting. So I'm just
going to look at this run and this is
what it looks like. Found the new file.
went through all of these steps,
downloaded it. Up here, it set one
variable for the notes, which is the
summary, and one for the raw
transcription. And then it pulled in the
recording here. It successfully went for
this router as we have everything we
need. And then back here, we get into
using the GPT API. Let me briefly switch
over to the editing mode so you can see
this. It's all within the blueprint that
we'll provide with this video. But as
you can see right here, this is a prompt
that we've worked out over several
months. Here are the different blocks we
wanted to include like the uncomfortable
truths like identifying action items,
listing longerterm high impact
opportunities and more. You can check
out all of this in here. Then we create
this JSON that is going to be the
structure that we'll be using for the
GPT call. So the system prompt at the
top and a transcription below it as
context. And then here you set your API
key and then you pull in this JSON to
give the API all the info it needs to
work properly. Hope that's making sense
in terms of calling the API. That's
pretty standard stuff. We've covered
this dozens of times on the channel.
Again, this is not exactly a beginner
tutorial. Let's move on. And then here
in the end, we do a bunch of formatting
steps so that all of this data can be
presented nicely within the air table.
And then, as you can see, it takes the
output of the last step here 58 to save
that within the air table summary field.
And if I look over to the air table,
that's exactly what happens. It goes
into here. And we can see the full
custom summary in here. So, as I
mentioned in the beginning, now we're
not just getting the standard Google
Gemini summary, which is, you know,
fine, but it gives me this in-depth
report here. So, there you go. That's a
semi-detailed overview of what this
actually does. And now I'm going to show
you how to actually import and activate
this for yourself because we exported
this automation as a make blueprint,
which you can in your free account even
import. All you need to do is go into a
new scenario, say import blueprint, and
then get the file from the link in the
description below. We'll put it up in a
public G drive for you to download. So,
I went through this process of setting
this up myself a few days ago now. And
really, there's three main things that
you need to change. First of all, you
need to switch this to your own
connections. So, all the Google Drive
notes, which are one, two, and then free
right here, need to be changed to your
own Google Google Drive. You're not
going to have access to our company
Google Drive obviously. And then you'll
also need to adjust the meeting folder.
Same thing goes for the Air Table
connection. By the way, quick note is
that you might have seen that in
previous tutorials we used a lot of
notion, but we actually switched to Air
Table for all of our automations just
because it's speedier. A lot of times we
saw errors from various automations,
especially with higher throughput and a
lot of data coming through. And we
needed some workarounds because Notion
is freely available and it can work as a
database, but if you put a lot of info
into something like a long transcript,
you would have to chunk it into
different pieces and do all of these
like data gymnastics just for it to work
in Notion. In Air Table, it just works
and it's speedier. The downside is that
it's paid, but for those reasons, we
switched everything over to air
tableable and that's what we're using
now. So, you'll have to reconnect that
too and you'll need a air table that is
set up like this. A name field that is a
single text line, a date field that is a
date text type, the Google doc link that
is a URL, a recording link which is also
a URL, and a summary which is a long
text field. If you have this set up in
Air Table, you'll add a new connection
right here. And then just make sure that
these exact variables link in the
various fields and this will work. The
same thing goes for this second air
table node here. And then most
importantly there's a third air
tableable node here in the end. So if
everything goes right, this is where it
saves all of that. If you just copy the
structure of this air table and you link
your account, it should be able to
transfer everything over smoothly from
the blueprint. So you just need to
switch out the connection, pick the
right base and table and all of this
should appear for you. Just in case you
need to recreate it, I'll show it all
like so. And then the last step is
actually changing the value here in the
OpenAI API call to your own API key. The
rest can stay the same. And that should
make this full automation work. In case
you run into troubles, you can always
create a screenshot, give that to GPT or
use some of the make documentation,
which is very extensive to help you make
some of these nodes work. Customizing
this to other tools is obviously a
different story, but I mentioned that in
the beginning. And once you have it all
working, here's my recommendation. You
can customize this. Okay, so each
organizations and each individual's
goals are going to be different. And the
point of this is that you can really go
into here and play with things like the
system prompt right here. And then at
the end of this prompt is the part that
is so crucial for you to customize
yourself. So if you scroll down here in
the preset, you will see this part that
says mission vision values that
specifies them and then the road map.
Now you can delete parts of this. For
example, now we're in Q4, so I won't
need these parts. Just make sure to
include what you're actually doing with
your company and what your actual
mission, vision, and values are for this
to work properly. Otherwise, it's not
going to know about you, right? So, I'm
just going to copy over our mission from
a file here on the other screen. Our
vision is over here kind of if you're
curious, I have like a notion knowledge
base where I take these things from. But
here, I'm just going to copy over the
vision. And then finally the values that
we kind of represent here and that I
hold my team to. And then for the road
map, I also have like a few road map
points on things that we're working on
right now. So I'm going to copy that
over like so. This is just these are
some items of our road map right here.
And then when this is updated at the
bottom, I'm going to make sure to save
this. Now the automation knows this and
every time it processes the transcript
it will include my very own mission
vision values and the road map from this
system prompt note. You can try
different ones. You can duplicate this
automation and maybe have two versions
of it with two databases where it runs
two different prompts every time and
then you can kind of split test and see
what you like better based on your
various meetings. Meetings are one of
the most powerful forms of context
across the internet and there's
something all of us do these days with
remote work environments and Zoom calls
being completely normal in most careers.
All of those can be transcribed and with
an automation like this you will be able
to extract all of the knowledge from
within that and it even allows you to do
something like hey if you have an
organization with let's say 30 employees
and there's a bunch of meetings going
on. Well this way you can be present in
all of them or at the very least you can
be scanning if everything that is being
done in the meetings actually aligns
with the road map that you set up.
That's extremely powerful. Another
example would be as chief marketing
officer overseeing the entire marketing
department and having a meeting analyzer
like this for each marketing meeting
that happens and then just getting these
reports and seeing what uncomfortable
truths are being avoided in the
meetings. That's usually where the
growth opportunities hide. I want to
show you one more thing to round this
out though. So this entire automation is
happening in make but as I told you
we're using air tableable as a database
and what we did here within Air Table is
set up a so-called interface. This is
something that they have on their
premium plans where it gives me this
manager dashboard and once the
automation is working, I don't have to
bother with that anymore. That's the
whole point, right? As an active
operator in my own company, I actually
want to go in here and interact with
this easily. And this interface that we
built here does that. So you can see the
various content meetings show up here.
And it doesn't just link to the Google
doc and the recording. It shows me the
entire custom summary. So right here, I
can see all the uncomfortable truths
from within here. And I have the same
thing running for all our weekly team
meetings, which is kind of a all hands
meeting, whereas the content meeting is
focused on the YouTube channel. And
that's the power of this. If you set it
up once, you can create these dashboards
for executive functions within a company
and give them a level of insight that
would never be possible manually. It
wouldn't be possible without LMS to
analyze the transcripts. It wouldn't be
possible without this digital work
revolution where everybody's using
Google Meets, Zoom, etc. to meet
remotely. And it also wouldn't be
possible with tools like make that
connect all of these variables and
produce results like this in the end. So
I hope this was helpful. You can find
the blueprint in the description below.
And again, a big thank you to Make for
actually pushing us to create this video
and to show you some of the advanced
workflows that are actually working for
us. All right, my name is Igor and I
hope you have a wonderful